JAMES SHAPCOTT

London, United Kingdom

Email: shapcott.james@outlook.com Mobile: (+44)07963894468

PERSONAL PROFILE

A Graduate of Games Computing from the University of Lincoln I am keen to build on the knowledge and experience gained through my degree course.

I am self-motivated and conscientious, and pride myself on being able to use my own initiative and am open to new experiences. I am flexible and adaptable in my own approach to work as well as being able to work under pressure, to tight deadlines and within set budgets, and am able to work effectively alone or as part of a team. As well as being resourceful with a mature attitude I am also reliable and have excellent interpersonal and communication skills.

I have completed both the Duke of Edinburgh Award up to Bronze standard and The Young Enterprise Scheme with my company coming second in the region. This has given me and developed my many key skills such as teamwork, communication, decision-making, time management, and planning.

In my spare time I have been working on personal projects to keep my skills up to date, including former University work.

SKILLS/TECHNOLOGY

- C#, C++, COBOL, Java, JavaScript, HTML, SQL
- Visual Studio, Eclipse, Maven, Git, Github/BitBucket
- OpenGL, PhysX, Eclipse, Unity3D, XNA/Mono
- Agile/SCRUM, waterfall
- Microsoft Office/Google office suite
- Full current, clean Driving Licence

PORTFOLIO

Github Portfolio

SELECT PROJECTS

C++

- PhysX modelling of a pinball machine physics, and physical objects created, playable game
- OpenGL modelling of an airport scene lighting, texture mapping, model construction
- Image Search searching an image for Where's Wally, using a reference image

C#

- Continuum247 Research/Development into a Welfare/shift logging system (mobile/phone), Debugging/error of existing code, written in C#
- #AI Map navigation A* algorithm implementation, user selects a start and finish point, and the program shows the shortest/quickest route between the two points
- "Top Trumps" style game user selects the category they think will beat the NPC card, and the game compares the values, determining the winner

Java

- Sopra Banking/NS&I Addition of Knowledge Based Authentication function for ID
- Sopra Banking/NS&I Tax Free Childcare development and upgrade

COBOL

- Sopra Banking/NS&I Help To Save development
- Sopra Banking/VTB Banking localisation for UK Market

Games

- Unity3d Horizon Game Jam prize winning game about some aliens that got lost in a desert
- Unity3d Armageddon my wheelchair Microsoft Kinect wheelchair mobility game
- GameMaker Curie Marie a game with radioactive Nazi's
- PhysX Pinball Machine

SQL

• Sopra Banking/NS&I – Database for all financial/user data – for application support, required SQL/Multi-table data aggregation to navigate and investigate issues

Application Support

- Sopra Banking/NS&I Application Support providing first/second-line support, dealing with incident requests coming from members of the public or colleagues within NS&I and providing support for issues such as:
 - Project go-live support
 - Providing code update recommendations
 - Providing password resets
 - Financial transaction corrections
 - Data correction

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

September 2012 – University of Lincoln Degree course - BSc Games Computing – Graduated with honours

June 2015 Modules: Software Development, Computer Systems, Operating Systems, Data Structures, Game

Design, Computer Graphics and Games Programming, Game Engines, Games Studies, Professional Practice, Group Project - game development, Final Year Project - Microsoft Kinect application

September 2004 – Newcastle upon - Tyne University
April 2006 Degree course - BSc Chemistry, 1 year

1996 – 2003 Branston Community College, Station Road, Lincoln

A - Levels Chemistry, Maths, Physics, General Studies, Young Enterprise UK Exam

GCSE 10 GCSE's including Single and Double Award Science Grade A, and Maths grade B

WORK EXPERIENCE

July 2019 – December 2019 Ventiv Technology – Application Support Analyst

• Application Support – providing first/second-line support, dealing with incident requests, providing support for issues

October 2016 – August 2018 Sopra Banking Software – Software Developer

- Developed banking system to handle money transfers and transactions, interest payments, client account creation
- NS&I Application Support providing first/second-line support, dealing with incident requests coming from members of the public or colleagues within NS&I and providing support for issues Project go-live support, Financial transaction corrections, providing password resets, Data correction, Providing code update recommendations, SQL database work
- NS&I addition of Knowledge Based Authentication function for use ID Java/JavaScript
- NS&I Tax Free Childcare development and upgrade Java
- NS&I Help to Save development COBOL
- VTB banking localisation for UK Market COBOL

December 2015 – March 2016 Continuum 24/7 – Software Developer

- Development of an online calendar system
- Provided onsite training for a client
- Welfare/shift logging system (phones) program would: allow users to log into the start of their shift, track the user's checkpoints through the shift, dial out to remind a user to log in, etc...

November 2005 – Sept 2012 Tesco's PLC General Assistant

• Stock distribution and movement, till work/Cashier, Managing the delivery, Price reduction of critical stock

August 2005 – 2008 Shine Photographics – Photographic Assistant

Assisting the Head Photographer in all areas

Sept 2003 – July 2004 Argos – Customer Advisor

• Till work, Customer Collection and Stock movement.

Sept 2001 – June 2002 Presentation Industries – Sales Director (For Young Enterprise)

- In charge of advertising, sales and marketing
- Writing and presenting the end of year speech to the Young Enterprise Schemes Board at the University of Lincoln

INTERESTS AND ACTIVITIES

- My interests include films, TV, reading and I enjoy playing video games.
- Sport: I enjoy playing team sport, I have played 5/6-a-side football, and captained my school cricket team
- My increasing interest in the production of video games led to the decision to further my understanding of this area by undertaking my degree course in Games Computing at the University of Lincoln.
- 24hr Game Jam:
 - 24hr Game Jams hosted by the University of Lincoln's Computing Society an annual event taking place in the spring.
 - Teams design and develop a game within a 24-hour period, where communication, teamwork and time management are key to producing the Game.
 - I won the title "Most Juicy", as part of Team Man-Beast, for the best use of theme in 2015.